chorn@chorn.com 585-520-1785

Skype: chornatchorn

Tagline

Friendly technologist & leader who loves programming.

Summary

My experience includes empty room to full stack Internet services, blank screen to SaaS, problem to feature, and crisis to solution. I am comfortable and effective at managing, mentoring, analysing, investigating, programming, planning, and coordinating. I collaborate with technologists and creatives just as easily as with sales and customers. I like small companies, big problems, smart teams, disruptive ideas, agility, simplicity, and good advice.

Titles and Roles

Engineering Manager, Architect, Product Owner, Generalist, Programmer, Developer, Lead Developer, Engineer, Consultant, Team Leader, Business Intelligence Manager, Teacher, Instructor, Mentor, and Adjunct Professor.

Technologies and Responsibilities

Recent projects utilizing Ruby, Rails, Elixir, Bash, Chef, Docker, AWS, RDS, MySQL, MariaDB, Percona, Postgres, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch.

Recent deliverables requiring Data Analysis, Strategic Planning, Project Management, Team Building, Pair Programming, Process Definition & Improvement, APIs, Natural Language Processing, Scaling, Fault Tolerance, Data Integrity, and Crisis Management.

Experience

PhishMe

2015-12 - Present Architect, Product Owner, and Manager of Software Engineering

2015-02 - 2015-12 Lead Developer - Simulator

Project lead for many of the most sensitive, complex, and important changes made to the Simulator product. Duties included managing cross-functional teams, interviewing, mentoring, pairing, collaborating, meeting delivery schedules, building reasonable solutions, and advocating for customers. Collaborated with multiple organizations within PhishMe to create engineering plans and requirements to meet the needs of the business, with respect to growth, maintenance, quality, security, and speed. Invented a technique for long-cycle, multi-developer refactoring that enabled the successful launch of a new product line. Responsible for the highly successful definition and growth of a Kanban project team to rescue a struggling Scrum implementation.

Metrix Matrix

1999 - 2015

Technology Generalist and C-Level Manager, responsible for most programming, database, network, security, purchasing, contracts, partnerships, and project management at MMI. Delivered, maintained, and monitored services for internal dependencies as well as the full stack of Internet services required to provide a SaaS. Responsibilities including project planning, vendors, contracts, compliance, hiring, mentoring, and budgets. Delivered over 50 internal projects for ETL, metrics, monitoring, and other core business functions. Special knowledge of data, surveys, telephony, APIs, analysis, and reporting.

University of Rochester

2006 - 2008

Adjunct Professor for the CS-108 course. Crafted course curriculum, tests, and lab assignments for the non-computer science major survey of technology course.

Synacor

2005 - 2006

Responsible for large data warehousing, reporting and statistical analysis project. Project manager for cross-functional teams building the new BI infrastructure. Designed and implemented extract, transform and load (ETL) software and database to process enterprise wide web server logs with 100 million hits a day. Designed data warehouse for storage and on- line analytical processing (OLAP) reporting.

Manning and Napier (MNIS)

1998 - 1999

Lead Engineer responsible for Mapit and Patentminer, two Intellectual Property search engines. Each were large projects, well over 100,000 LOC in a combination of Perl, C, Java, and Javascript.

Spherion (Interim Technology)

1997 - 1998

Assessment, presentation, requirements gathering, and implementation of CMM, SPI, and Y2K projects.

Thomson Reuters (WestGroup)

1994 - 1997

Technical Lead for the Verification and Validation group. Managed the project and technical direction of Software Quality Assurance group, including human resources tasks of interviews and annual performance reviews. Assessment, documentation, verification, validation, and automation of electronic legal reference products. Created a test automation platform in DOS.

Education

State University of New York at Buffalo Monroe Community College

B.S., Computer Science A.S., Computer Science

Affiliations

Greece Volunteer Ambulance BarCamp Rochester

2003 - 2008 2008 - Present

EMT-B, Driver Organizer

Rochester.rb Hacks/Hackers Rochester

2008 - Present 2012 - Present

Organizer Organizer

Coderetreat Hour of Code

2013 - Present 2014 - Present

Facilitator Teacher

Awards

1st Place, National Fuel Gas Energy Awareness Programming Contest 1986

Internet and Social

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/chorn

GitHub https://github.com/chorn

Twitter https://twitter.com/chorn

Blog http://chorn.com/